<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stat1010 on Issac Lee</title>
    <link>/tags/stat1010/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stat1010 on Issac Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/stat1010/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7 - Mean, Median, and Weighted Mean</title>
      <link>/post/stat1010-week7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stat1010-week7/</guid>
      <description>Let us assume that we have following data set;
50, 80, 60, 90, 70MeanThe mean is the sum of all values in a data set divided by the number of values in the data set.
\[mean = \frac{50 + 80 + 60 + 90 + 70}{5} = 70\]
Q. What is the mean of these numbers?
10, 11, 21, 13, 20, 16  Answer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8 - Measure for the spread of distributions</title>
      <link>/post/stat1010-week8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stat1010-week8/</guid>
      <description>Let us assume that we have following data set;
50, 80, 60, 90, 70Now, we want to talk about the spread of our data. There are som
RangeThe range is one of the measures that captures the spread of the data, which can be calculated by subtracing the minimum of the data set from the maximum of the data set.
\[\begin{aligned}Range &amp;amp; = max(data) - min(data) \\&amp;amp; = 90 - 50 = 40\end{aligned}\]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9 - 68-95-99.5 rules</title>
      <link>/post/stat1010-week9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stat1010-week9/</guid>
      <description>Normal distributionFrom the basic statistics course, we are already familiar with a bell-shape distribution called Normal distribution.
Here are some characteristics of all Normal curves;
- Symmetric, Unimodal- It can be specified by its mean and standard deviation.- Mean is related to center of the distribution.- Sd controls the spread of the distribution.- All Normal distribution obey the 68-95-99.7 rule.Our textbook use the following notation for refering a specific normal distribution;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5 - Freq. table and Stem plot</title>
      <link>/post/stat1010-week5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stat1010-week5/</guid>
      <description>Let us assume that we have following data set;
67, 61, 68, 80, 63, 75, 62, 66, 56, 72, 53, 79, 76, 54, 70HistogramIf I draw a histogram with the above data using 5 bins, it looks like the following plot.
Q. Can you draw the histogram with 3 bins? What does it look like?
Answer
Stem-and-Leaf plotA stemp plot consists of two parts;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4(STAT:1010) - Describe what you have in your data</title>
      <link>/post/stat1010-week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stat1010-week4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;More than&amp;rdquo; vs. &amp;ldquo;Of&amp;rdquo; Definitions:
 Using &amp;ldquo;of&amp;rdquo;
In a class, there are 30 students. By the policy of the university, 10% of the class will get &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; grades. How many people would get &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; at the end of the semester?
 Using &amp;ldquo;more than&amp;rdquo;
Issac runs an ice cream store and today he got 100 customers. He wants to forecast the number of tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s customers using statistical method. After the study, he predicts that the number of the customers will be 50% more than today&amp;rsquo;s customer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3(STAT:1010) - Data type and errors</title>
      <link>/post/stat1010-week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stat1010-week3/</guid>
      <description>Problem 1 (Data types) Definitions:
 Qualitative data: values that can be placed into nonnumerical categories.
 Nominal level of measurement - No ranking!
 Ordianl level of measurement - It has ranking system!
  Quantitative data: values representing counts or measurments
 Countinuous data takes any value in a given interval.
 Discrete data can take on only particular, distinct values and not other values in between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics and Society (STAT:1010)</title>
      <link>/post/stat1010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stat1010/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my discussion section for STAT:1010.
Issac (Sak) Lee  Office location: 213 SH Office hour: Friday 2pm - 5pm Email: sak-lee@uiowa.edu
Please put a tag STAT:1010 in front of your title when you email me.
  Attendance policy We have 13 weeks for this semester. You will get 3 free absences. Thus, your attendance will counts as 1 point and you will get 10 points in total from this discussion section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2(STAT:1010)</title>
      <link>/post/stat1010-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stat1010-week2/</guid>
      <description>Problem 1 A large warehouse is flled with light bulbs. An electronics engineer wants to estimate the mean lifespan of these bulbs. To this end, 18 of the bulbs were randomly selected and the lifespan was measures; the mean lifespan of the 18 bulbs was 2550 hours.
 What is the population? What is the sample? What is the parameter? What is the sample statistics?  Problem 2 In a survey of 400 randomly selected UI students, 30% of students said they like a chocolate ice cream.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>